<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>vector|adventures</title><link href="jakemick.github.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="jakemick.github.com/feeds/books.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>jakemick.github.com/</id><updated>2012-12-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>Review of Techical Blogging</title><link href="jakemick.github.com/review-of-techical-blogging.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Jake Mick</name></author><id>tag:jakemick.github.com,2012-12-02:review-of-techical-blogging.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;POST IN PROGRESS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Techical Blogging: Turn Your Expertise into a Remarkable Online Presence
by Antonio Cangiano&lt;/em&gt; is offered by The Pragmatic Bookshelf at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pragprog.com/book/actb/technical-blogging/"&gt;PragProg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;From the site:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Technical Blogging is the first book to specifically teach programmers,
technical people, and technically-oriented entrepreneurs how to become
successful bloggers. There is no magic to successful blogging; with this book
you’ll learn the techniques to attract and keep a large audience of loyal,
regular readers and leverage this popularity to achieve your goals.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that that is out of the way, the rest of this post is aimed at being as
&lt;strong&gt;meta-edgy&lt;/strong&gt; as I possible can, abusing &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/user/rst/quickref.html"&gt;reStructuredText&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/3.0/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; while
writing a review of &lt;em&gt;Technical Blogging&lt;/em&gt; on a technical blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phew&lt;/em&gt;. So let's get down to the d33ts. I follow a bunch of technical reading
circles and blogs. I read so much $LaTeX$ that I speak in $\int$s, but I
haven't contribute to much besides some Q/A on StackExchange and r/&lt;a href="#id1"&gt;&lt;span class="problematic" id="id2"&gt;MachineLearning_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2013 will the year that this changes. So I downloaded a copy of
Technical Blogging*. It has been a joy to read. The book is written in the style
similar to the documentation surrounding a programming framework. There's a solid
introduction establishing the purpose of the domain, &amp;quot;Blogging isn't dead, it is a
... Here's how this book fits in...&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chapters that follow are self-contained units implicitly forcing you to answer questions
while concretizing the blog idea you have in mind. The author suggests writing down a plan of action
as you parse the book. The chapters give you advice on WordPress then go on to
give Dos-and-Donts about SEO, content creation, post consistency, reading Analytics,
building a following, blog-growth and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the title I had expected a book focused on writing, but it is a small fraction
of the book. The author agrees that content is the most important aspect of a blog
but much of the book is devoted to all of the things surrounding a blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a fascinating way to approach blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;37Signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Looks great in Vim, btw.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="screenshot.png" class="align-right" src="screenshot.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- JakeMick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="system-messages section"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Docutils System Messages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message" id="id1"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: ERROR/3 (&lt;tt class="docutils"&gt;/srv/repos/adventures_in_vectors/content/notes_on_technical_blog.rst&lt;/tt&gt;, line 26); &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="#id2"&gt;backlink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Unknown target name: &amp;quot;machinelearning&amp;quot;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="books"></category><category term="blogging"></category><category term="writing"></category></entry></feed>