<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>vector|adventures</title><link href="jakemick.github.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="jakemick.github.com/feeds/cars.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>jakemick.github.com/</id><updated>2012-12-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>Most popular days to shop for a car</title><link href="jakemick.github.com/most-popular-days-to-shop-for-a-car.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Jake Mick</name></author><id>tag:jakemick.github.com,2012-12-02:most-popular-days-to-shop-for-a-car.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="disclaimer"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;DISCLAIMER:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This data is fabricated. I wrote this to show off my writing and plotting skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A car is a big purchase. Few of us buy one on an impulse. You decide that
you're going to buy a car, you narrow it down to a few models and you're
almost ready to pull the trigger when you get a massive salary bump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You call your wife to tell her. She informs you that your daughter needs
braces and your dog went through your savings on online Poker. (Screenname: d3vil_Bernard2004)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ye olde cocktail napkin reveals that you're still up $290/month. The BMW in the back
of your head through lunch seems within reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is crazy. Your budget oscillates wildly, but you have to pull the trigger
before the Fiesta dies in rush-hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-chaos"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Chaos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is our attempt to explore the trends in the chaos of U.S. budgets for
new cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="car-sale-daily.png" class="align-right" src="car-sale-daily.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The magenta line is the 100,000's of car sales we processed each day in 2011.
Sales jumps up and down consistently depending on where we on in a month.
There doesn't appear to be a trend for different seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="car-sale-daily-trend.png" class="align-right" src="car-sale-daily-trend.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking just at the trend it becomes apparent that the there is a massive
200,000+ swing in sales that takes place through the month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="car-sale-daily-trend-monthy.png" class="align-right" src="car-sale-daily-trend-monthy.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can zoom in on the trend for a given month. Right around the 10th there's
a spike in sales. Followed by a slow decline to the low around the 25th. On
average our customers sign their leases half-way between billing cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See? The chaos alluded to at the top of this post is cyclical for
U.S. households. How likely you are to purchase a car depends on many factors,
but these factors come in monthly trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you on the 10th. -- JakeMick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="visualization"></category><category term="data"></category><category term="cars"></category></entry></feed>